hello everybody and welcome to part 3 in
大家好，欢迎来到GMOD LUA教程系列
the gmod Louis series now in this video
第三部分，这期视频
it's gonna be pretty short I do
这期视频非常的短
apologize and there is a game gonna be
很惭愧这期视频内
no programming or scripting but that is
不会有直接编程或脚本相关的内容
because there is something that I can't
这是因为有一个东西
stress enough and I want to make sure
我无论如何也要给大家强调
you understand and that is the Garry's
也希望大家知晓的，那就是
Mod wiki this is the most important
Garry's Mod的wiki百科，这是我能给你的
thing I can give you now anything you
最宝贵的礼物，你写代码所需要
will ever need is on this wiki and if I
参考的一切都在这个额wiki上
explain to something to you that you
如果我给你介绍的东西
don't fully understand then you can go
你感到困惑的话，你可以打开
ahead and look it up on here and
Wiki的网站，然后参阅那里面的相关资料
there'll be all of the information you
那里有你需要的一切信息
need on here now let's say for example
现在我们举个栗子吧
this search feature here let's say I
这里有个搜索功能，如果我
want to know how to kill a player I
想知道怎样杀死一个玩家
might search kill and I'll see you
我可以搜索关键词kill，然后我可以看到/
player kill over here now as you can see
左边出现了Player:Kill条目，如你所见
it tells me the function name I will
它告诉了我这个函数的名字，我会
explain what this is in in another
在另一篇教程里解释这个函数名的含义
tutorial and it tells me that it kills
它告诉我这个函数会杀死
the player and cause GM played F again I
玩家，然后引发GM:PlayerDeath事件
don't expect you to understand this
再次说明一下，我不是要你立刻理解这些全部内容
right now but once we get over the
不过当我们把基础知识全部过了一遍之后
basics this is gonna be your your main
WIKI就成了你最主要的
place to hang out whenever you're
参考资料，无论何时你在编写脚本的时候
scripting you'll pretty much always have
你都需要经常打开wiki
the wiki open now just because you use
这是因为，你开着wiki写代码
the wiki it doesn't mean you're a bad
并不意味着你很菜
coder you can go ahead and find the best
你可以去问问那些顶尖的开发者
coder out there and I guarantee you
我向你保证
they'll be like well yeah I use the wiki
他们也和我一样一直在使用wiki
for the most of my things because it's
去做大部分的工作，因为
not something that anybody can remember
很显然没有人有那么好的记忆力
there is just so much information here
这个游戏有太多的信息了
that just simply a single person could
一个人显然很难记住
not memorize it all there is just too
全部的信息
much so again there will be a link to
所以在简介里我会放上
the wiki in the description make sure
wiki的链接，请确保你
you always have it on backup if you're
在收看我的视频的时候
watching my videos just open this in the
在后台开着wiki的网页
background and if I say something that
如果我在视频里介绍了什么
you're not too sure on just go ahead and
你不太懂的东西，你可以立刻打开wiki
look it up on the wiki and there'll be
然后搜索相关内容
all the information you need on it on
那里会有你需要的一切信息
there now again once we get a few videos
当你继续收看几期视频之后
in you will also begin to understand how
你也会逐渐理解
the wiki works because we'll go into
wiki对你有怎样的帮助，因为接下来我们将
more depth as we go on and with that
进一步的学习GMOD的脚本开发
you'll be able to create cool things and
这意味着你能做一些更cool的东西
figure out what these functions do and
同时你也需要理解这些函数的功能
use them to your own advantage so again
并利用他们做出你想要的效果
I apologize for a short video but if you
很抱歉视频还是很短
have any questions leave a comment below
不过如果你还有什么疑问的话可以在评论区里留言
I hope you enjoyed watching and I'll see
希望你看的高兴
you in the next video
我们下个视频再见
you